要帮忙吗
You need any help?
不用
I got it.
那我帮你擦干
I'll just dry, then.
不用
It's okay.
-唐娜  唐娜  -不行
- Donna. Donna! - Nope.
我受够了天天内疚
I am done feeling bad about this.
都一个星期了  你的意思我已经明白了
It's been a week. You've made your point.
你今晚得跟我上床睡
You're sleeping in the bed with me tonight.
快去
Get in there.
我还生你气呢
I'm still very mad at you.
不骗你
I am!
戈登  能去睡了吗
Gordon, can we go to bed now?
天啊  这是怎么回事
Sheesh, what happened here?
不知道  也许掉下来了吧
I don't know. Maybe it fell?
从房间一头飞到另一头吗
Across the room?
也许响得太频繁了吧
Maybe it was ringing too much.
-那个又是怎么回事  -灾难性故障
- How about there? - Catastrophic failure.
你需要一个剥线器
You're gonna need wire strippers.
是啊
Looks like it, don't it?
我得去我车上找找
I'd better run out to my truck.
给
Here.
用我的
Use mine.
电话公司一年到头都缺人
You know, phone company's always hiring.
用完放桌上就行
Okay, so just leave them on the desk when you're done.
你们造的这台电脑  外壳上写的什么
This computer y'all built, what's it say on the outside?
我们明白你的意思
I think we get your point.
写的什么
What does it say?
卡迪夫电子
Cardiff Electric.
写着卡迪夫电子
It says Cardiff Electric.
那是谁的名字
Whose name is that?
我跟电脑天地签了十万台的合同
I closed ComputerLand at 100,000 units.
3月1日电脑就要上市了
We'll be in stores March 1.
我们的净盈利预计会超过四千万
You're looking at a projected net profit of over $40 million.
我65岁了
I'm 65 years old.
既然我可以卖个五百万
Why would I want $40 million
从此退休养老  我干嘛还要四千万  小子
when I can settle for five and just kick back, Jack?
我的电话也被打爆了
My phone's been ringing, too,
人们想买下这家公司
people wanting to buy this company outright.
他们提出了丰厚的条件要我放弃她
They've been offering me a lot of change to close her down.
这间办公室
This office...
外面怎么写的
what does it say outside?
大厅的牌子上怎么写的
The sign in the lobby, what does it say?
说话小心点  小子
You be careful, boy.
写着卡迪夫电子  那是谁的名字
It says Cardiff Electric. Whose name is that?
不只是您的  还是您父亲的  对吧
Not just yours. Your father's, right?
创立于1934年
Started in 1934,
在朗维尤制造短波收音机起家
shortwave radios manufactured out of Longview.
我听说他亲自管理工厂
I heard he ran the factory floor himself.
这不是为了钱
I'm not talking about money.
而是传承
I'm talking about legacy.
公司完全转向经营个人电脑
The company shifts entirely into personal computing.
缩减开销  增加利润
Overhead shrinks, profits grow.
让我来经营  卡迪夫电子会摆脱冗杂
You let me run this, Cardiff Electric becomes nimble
更加适合21世纪
and ready for the 21st century.
你俩一起管
You both run it.
平起平坐
As equals...
因为你是一条响尾蛇
because you are a rattlesnake,
而你是一只小白兔
and you-- you're a little bunny rabbit,
但你是研发计算机的技术人员
but you're the brains behind this thing.
好
Fine.
我俩各持公司8%的股份
Eight percent of the company,
全面摊薄
fully diluted,
1年后开始兑现股份  期满4年全部兑现
four-year vesting, cliff at one year for each of us.
我就该把你杀了埋了
You know, I should just bury you in a shallow grave.
找别人来管理这个公司
I should get somebody else in here to run this company.
或者自己管理  还能省笔钱
Hell, I should save a few bucks and just run it myself.
那祝你好运了
Good luck with that.
你准备把工厂建在本地  还是省点钱建在台湾
You gonna manufacture locally or in Taiwan to save some coin?
日本的出口设施更好
Japan has better output facilities,
但是关税太高了
but the tariffs are tricky.
要是你知道该找谁
You might be able to do a deal
或许可以跟英特尔谈下批发的合同
with Intel in bulk if you know who to talk to,
不过他还同时管理IBM的批发业务
but it's the same guy who manages IBM's bulk deal,
所以得下点功夫
so it'll take some massaging.
不久就要改用286  转投AMD
Go 286 in the near future and switch to AMD.
绕过英特尔
Bypass Intel.
而且AMD的产品一般运行更快
Especially since AMD parts almost always clock faster.
兆赫配置  低价买入
Megahertz, minimum bucks.
不过我也说不好  你怎么看  内森
But I don't know. What do you think, Nathan?
-8%  -每人
- Eight percent. - Each.
你们平分
Split.
也行
We can live with that.
那走着瞧了
We'll see, won't we?
巨人  觉醒啦
The Giant awakens!
好了  这是制造商发来的第一批样机
All right, this is the first test shipment from the manufacturer.
这里有一百台
We got 100 machines here,
我需要所有人都来调试这些机子
so I need all hands on deck QA-ing these boxes.
硬件  软件  像素噪点  接口等等
Hardware, software, failed pixels, I/O ports...
-弹性张力  -弹性张力  没错
- Pinch tension. - Pinch tension,
还有内温  适配程度
internal temp, fit and finish.
检查电脑的每个细节
Check every millimeter of this machine.
巨人六周内就要发货
The Giant ships out in less than six weeks.
一定要做到完美
It must be perfect!
黛比
Debbie.
戈登  我不知道怎么做电脑评测
Gordon, I don't know how to test a computer.
不  这是送你的
No, this is for you.
你忍了我和乔那么久
I figured you put up with me and Joe long enough,
这是你应得的
you deserve one.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你看到乔了吗
Have you seen Joe?
-他在博斯沃思的办公室  -好的  谢谢
- He's in Bosworth's office. - Okay. Thanks.
我还想你什么时候会霸占这间好办公室呢
I wondered how long it'd take till you took the corner office.
我就是要用电视
I just needed the TV.
我们的第一批样机送到了
Our first test shipment came in.
我让每个人都仔细进行检查
I got everybody going over it with a fine-tooth comb.
你错过昨天的超级碗了吗
Did you miss the Bowl yesterday?
-录下来了  -反正红人都输了...
- I taped it on VHS. - Well, the Redskins still lose, so...
别管比赛了  看看这个广告
Forget about the game. Watch this commercial.
-乔  -这多棒
- Joe... - Tell me that wasn't amazing.
这是不是你见过的
Tell me that wasn't the best piece of marketing
业内最好的广告
you've ever seen in this industry.
是挺不错
Yeah, it was neat.
那个长得像卡梅伦的女孩
The girl that looked like Cameron
把锤子砸向屏幕
threw the sledgehammer through the screen
解放了一群奇怪的奴隶
and freed the weird slave people.
他们在向世界宣布他们要推翻IBM
They're telling the world that they're going to topple IBM.
好吧  但我没看到有电脑出现啊
Okay, well, I also didn't see a computer anywhere in sight.
据我对那些人的了解
My guess is, knowing those guys,
麦金托什只是空有花头  没什么用处
the Macintosh is all bells and whistles and zero utility.
你想要个玩具  买他们的
You want a toy, you buy one of those.
你想要台电脑  当然要买我们的
You want a computer, you buy one of ours.
人们会买巨人  但是他们会记住巨人吗
People will buy the Giant, but will they remember it?
如果我们把发货推迟几个月
If we delay shipping just a few months--
绝对不行  我们要进行测评
Absolutely not. We need to QA,
让制造商开始大批量生产  然后发货
give manufacturing the full green light, and ship.
你不想做大点吗
Don't you want it to be great?
乔  我们总改来改去
Joe, we keep futzing with this thing,
最后它就变成雾件了
it's gonna end up vaporware.
指已宣布但却未实现的产品
采用图形用户界面怎么样
What about a graphical user interface?
我们可以做一个图形用户界面
We could do a GUI--
乔  现实点
Joe, be realistic.
卡梅伦的操作系统就够拖慢速度了
You think Cameron's OS slowed things down?
我们的硬件根本不能...
We don't even have hardware that's capable of doing--
那就出一款杀手应用A killer app, then.
极度成功受欢迎的电脑软件
我们设计一款前所未见的软件
We design a phenomenal piece of software,
和电脑捆绑成套装发售
bundle it with the machine as a suite.
戈登  我们自己的Lotus 1-2-3是什么
Gordon, what's our "Lotus 1-2-3"?
就是别人的Lotus 1-2-3
Our "Lotus 1-2-3"? It's "Lotus 1-2-3."
我们造了一款IBM兼容机
We built an IBM compatible machine.
你想造一台电脑  你也造出来了
You wanted a computer. You have a computer.
造出来就得卖  明白吗
You need to sell your computer, okay?
她确实很像卡梅伦
She really did look like Cameron.
再说一下  本次调查
And again, this is strictly
纯粹是为了掌握我接管的这个部门的概况
to get a sense of the department I'm inheriting.
请用以下词组回答每一个问题
Please answer each of the questions with one of the following,
包括出类拔萃  进展显著  进行顺利
"Leading the way," "Moving ahead," "Right on track,"
明显落后  完全失控
"Falling behind," Or "Off track."
你如何评述你的工作质量
How would you rate the quality of your work overall?
明显落后
"Falling behind."
能详细说一下吗
Care to clarify?
说实话  亨特离职后我就一直心不在焉
Honestly, I've been very distracted since Hunt left--
抱歉  惠特马什先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Whitmarsh--
有那么一段时间  我真的陷于...
and for a while there, I was really caught up in--
我倒不认为那是婚外情
I wouldn't call it an affair.
大概算情感出轨吧
An emotional affair, maybe.
但随后他开了一家公司
But then he left to start a company
兜售他从我丈夫那儿偷的点子
based on ideas he stole from my husband, so...
你如何评价你工作的及时性
How would you rate the timeliness of your work?
-完全失控  -为什么
- Off track. - And why's that?
我11月私自跑去维加斯待了3天
I went to Vegas in November for three days
假都没请
and I didn't tell anybody.
那好吧
Okay.
你觉得你在德州仪器的发展前景如何
How do you feel about your future at Texas Instruments?
你能不能...能否写个"无答案"
Do you think-- could you just write "N/A"?
因为老实说  我觉得没什么前途
Because, honestly, I don't see one.
我们可以给你两周时间做准备
I suppose we could give you two weeks.
其实  我由衷希望今天就是我在职最后一天
Actually, I would really prefer if today were my last day.
我能请你吃午餐吗  女士
Can I take you to lunch, ma'am?
-我被炒啦  -恭喜
- I got fired. - Congratulations.
我贷款买的  他们简直是白送车
I financed it. They were practically giving them away.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
我觉得这是我见过的最花哨的奢侈品了
I think it's about the gaudiest exorbitance I've ever seen.
人人都会嫉妒得两眼放光的
And everyone's gonna be looking at us when we drive in it.
让他们嫉妒吧
Let 'em.
图像压缩程序太棒了
Graphics compression program is amazing.
相位调制也很好
So is phase modulation.
速率稳定在2400波特We're stable at 2400 baud.
信息传输速率单位
我的固件运行的还行吗
How's my firmware holding up?
调制解调器没问题
Modem's solid.
你有访问这些东西的权限吗
Hey, you authorized to access any of this stuff?
南部电信
逗呢你  要是被上头发现  得把他们气死
Are you kidding? If the suit found out, he'd shit a brick.
你知道我们能在3B5上建立多少连接吗
You know how many connections we can carry on the 3B5?
美国电话电报公司生产的电脑系统
我们甚至可以在这上面玩《魔域》
We can play "Zork" On this.
我们甚至可以自己写个游戏
We can make our own "Zork,"
就叫《巫师  战士和猛兽》
"Wizard, Warrior, Rogue."
天啊  你们满脑子都是《龙与地下城》那一套
God, everything is "Dungeons and Dragons" With you guys.
-你得承认这太酷了  -我知道
- You have to admit, this is pretty cool. - Yeah, I know.
拿给你老板看  如果他们知道
Show your boss. People would flip
在电话线上传送数据能这么快  得兴奋死
if they could move data this fast across the phone network.
那我们可就做不成电话公司了
Well, then we don't get to be the phone company anymore.
-我看打补丁也不见得能行  -怎么了
- We're probably not even talking about a patch. - What?
出什么事了
What is it?
发现一个1级严重性问题
Found a sev-one problem with the Giant.
是工艺问题还是设计问题
Manufacturing or design?
如果是工艺问题  我可以打电话问
'Cause if it's manufacturing, I can make a call.
说实话  我们还不知道
Honestly, we don't know yet.
什么意思
What do you mean you don't know yet?
我们可以让问题再现  查出其根源
We can repro it and we're trying to pin it down.
机器现在自动关机
It's causing the machine to turn off spontaneously.
-所有的样机吗  -不  只是黛比的
- All the test machines? - No, just Debbie's.
你做了什么  你摔地上了吗
What did you do to it? Did you drop it?
-你洒上东西了吗  -没有
- Did you spill something on it? - No.
-你借给你的男朋友了吗  -没有
- Did you lend it to your boyfriend or something? - No, none of that.
-黛比  你做了什么  -我什么都没做
- Debbie, what did you do? - I didn't do anything.
这是精密机器
These are delicate machines.
你不能就随手扔进你的后备箱里
You can't just throw them in the trunk of your car.
-戈登  对不起  -你得小心对待
- Gordon, I'm sorry. - You've gotta be careful with them.
硬件都正常  问题不在这儿
None of the hardware appears damaged. That's not the issue.
那我们手里有个劣品
Then we got a bad egg.
目前为止五台机器出一台劣品
One bad egg out of the five we've touched so far.
瑕疵率为五分之一  那一共就是两万台电脑
Say one in five computers has the flaw? That's 20,000 units.
-电脑天地会收到两万台退货  -没错
- That's 20,000 store returns at ComputerLand. - Exactly.
-一切都好吗  -不  出现了一个问题
- Everything all right? - No, we have a problem.
-有多糟  -我们还不知道
- Ooh, how bad? - We don't know yet.
严重性大概是2级  3级吧
Sev-two, sev-three maybe.
严重性等级划分为数字越小越严重
会影响出货吗
Oh, will it delay shipment?
我们得检查每一台样机
Well, we'll have to check every test unit.
或许这是个机遇
Maybe this is an opportunity.
我们延迟一两个月上架  修复漏洞
Maybe we delay a month or two to fix the bug
提高性能
and make some improvements.
到了三月  电脑天地就会有空货架了
Then come March, ComputerLand will have a bunch of empty shelves.
我都让丹尼斯二月底从新泽西
I already got Dennis flying in first class from New Jersey
坐头等舱来参加发布仪式了
at the end of February for the public launch.
别计较机票钱和派对费用了
This is bigger than plane fares and party costs.
我们在查补漏洞时
We got software just sitting around
软件工程师都在无所事事
while we figure out what's wrong.
我去让他们设计一个杀手应用
Let me run with them and build a killer app.
等到漏洞成功修复
By the time the bug is fixed,
我们在电脑天地上架的就不光是台电脑了
ComputerLand won't just have a computer,
而是一组套装
they'll have a bundled suite.
对我们又是优势了
We'll be out ahead again.
是喜事一桩吧
Now that's something to celebrate.
我知道这很遗憾
Look, I know this is unfortunate.
但人生就是要变劣势为优势  对吧
But life gives you lemons, right?
听好
Okay, listen up.
出货要延期
We've had a little hiccup with shipping,
所以我们多了些额外的时间
which means we've got some extra time,
作为软件工程师
and because we're who we are,
我们不能浪费时间玩游戏  发呆
we're not gonna spend it playing "Pong" and twiddling our thumbs.
我们得好好利用
We're gonna capitalize.
我知道你们一直摩拳擦掌想写些
I know you've been chomping at the bit to write something
外围驱动软件之外的东西
that's not a peripheral driver.
很好  因为从今天起  卡迪夫电子
Good, because today, Cardiff Electric
正式进军应用软件领域
has entered the software application business,
60天后
and in 60 days,
我要一款能和"巨人"一起发货的杀手应用
I want a killer app ready to ship with the Giant.
一流的软件配我们一流的机器
A top-notch program for our top-notch machine.
现在畅所欲言  我想听听你们的想法
Now this is blue sky. You got ideas, I wanna hear 'em.
然后付诸实践
And then I want us to make them.
你们愿意接受挑战吗
You guys up for a challenge like that?
绝对
You bet.
很好  很好  很好
Good, good, good.
第一天不上班怎么样啊
Hey, how was your first day off?
很满足
It was euphoric.
女儿们在哪
Where are the girls?
在外面过夜呢
Sleepover.
你想来一发吗
Do you wanna have one of our own?
有多糟
So, how bad is it?
出货肯定得推迟了
It's definitely gonna delay shipping.
我觉得是乔干的
I think Joe did it on purpose.
这对他有什么好处
I-I don't understand the benefit.
他根本不现实
He can't live in reality.
他总是在追逐空想
He's always chasing some fantasy, you know?
他从不知满足
He's never satisfied.
我不知道他的最终目的是什么
I don't know what his endgame is.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
事实是我无法信任他
The truth is that I can't trust him.
你那么努力
Hey, you have worked too hard
冒了那么大的风险才走到今天  还有我
and risked too much to get here. We both have.
不能允许任何人搞破坏
Nothing can be allowed to jeopardize that.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我想你懂我的意思
I think you know what I'm saying.
我找了三个小队检测3B5
I've got three teams running diagnostics on the 3B5,
看你是不是破坏了它
checking to see if you've corrupted it in any way.
还有人在检查网络本身是否受损
Also got guys checking the network itself to see if it's damaged.
伊莱  你不会这么笨吧
Come on, Eli. You're not that dumb.
你该知道网速其实可以快很多吧
You know the network can transmit way faster than we're letting it.
我们可以相移  调幅  插入纠错
We can phase shift, modulate amplitude, insert error correction --
基本上我们想做什么都行
basically whatever we want.
你们的调制解调器没经过认证
Your modems were uncertified.
网络访问条款是我们控制的  你懂吗
We dictate the terms of how the network is accessed. You understand?
让我猜猜
So, let me guess.
南部电信也要建立自己的数据网络啦
Southern Lines is setting up its own data network?
你到底在为谁工作
Who do you really work for?
没谁  现在没了
Nobody. Not anymore.
唐娜  工作物品
都有什么想法
All right, what do we got?
来吧  我们好好讨论一下
Come on, let's fire it up.
你  说说你的想法
You, let's hear it.
一个月相日历
It's a moon phase calendar.
只要你输入日期  它就能给出
So you type in the date and it gives you the upcoming
之后25年里的月相
phases of the moon for the next 25 years.
比如  我生于1997年
So, like, on my birthday in 1997,
那就是个盈凸月
it's going to be a waxing gibbous.
好吧  还有吗
Okay. What else?
你来
You.
准备好  因为你一定会爱上它
Careful, you're gonna love this.
仿真软件  养蜂人
A simulator -- beekeeping.
全仿真模式
Full-on "Zimulation." hardcore.
一开始有三个蜂巢  然后你可以...
You start with three hives and you're able --
各位  杀手应用应该让人爱不释手
Guys, a killer app is something that everyone wants,
无法自拔
they must have.
构想要宏伟
Think bigger.
难道卡梅伦是这儿惟一真正有创意的人吗
What, so Cameron was the only one of you that had any real ideas?
那你又有什么创意  哥们
Well, what are your ideas, man?
唐娜
Donna...
我知道怎么做了
I know how I'm gonna do it.
说来听听
Lay it on me.
乔的弱点是什么
What is Joe's Achilles' heel?
休闲装
Casual wear.
不  是卡梅伦
No, Cameron.
他爱上了她  你知道吗
He's in love with her, you know?
我当然知道  你居然才知道吗
Of course I know that. What planet have you been on?
我要去向联调局告发她
I'm gonna turn her in to the feds
和博斯沃思一起入侵电脑
for hacking with Bosworth
除非乔离开卡迪夫
unless Joe leaves Cardiff.
这是不是太邪恶了点
Isn't that a little bit evil?
就为了摆脱乔你就要毁掉卡梅伦的一生吗
You're gonna ruin Cameron's entire life just to get rid of Joe?
放心  我又不会真去
Relax. I'm not actually gonna do it.
只是用来吓唬他的
I'm just gonna threaten to.
乔不会上当的
Joe's too smart for that.
如果被他看出你只是虚张声势
What happens when he calls your bluff
并没有胆量真去告发怎么办
and realizes you don't have the stomach to go through with it?
-不不不  -等等  除非
- No, no, no, no. - Wait, wait, unless...
你拿出证据
you show him proof.
比如银行守护程序的上传记录
Like this uplink from the bank's daemon.
这里显示交易代码的更改
It shows the alteration of transaction codes
能追踪到卡梅伦办公室的电脑上
all routed back to Cameron's office computer.
唐娜  这是打印驱动程序
Donna, this is a print driver.
乔又不知道
Joe doesn't know that.
没你我做不来
I can't do this without you.
做什么  乔
Do what, Joe?
卡梅伦
Cameron...
回卡迪夫吧
come back to Cardiff.
你想做什么都行
You can do whatever you want.
给你全权委托...
You'll have carte blanche--
-不行  -那好  别给卡迪夫干
- No. - Fine, don't work for Cardiff.
自己办公司  我找你做分包
Form your own company. I'll hire you as a vendor.
你可以不用见我  我...我需要你
You'll never have to see my face. I just-- I need you.
天哪  你真可悲
Oh, God, you're pathetic.
我们自己办公司
We can start our own company.
我离开卡迪夫
I'll leave Cardiff.
我们可以去加州  去哪都行
We can go to California, go anywhere.
白手起家
We can start from scratch.
我想和你在一起
I wanna be with you.
听着不错
That sounds nice.
我们合作造点什么东西
We could build something together, a partnership.
开创自己的未来
Make our own future.
不过你不是未来
Except you're not the future.
你只是个陪衬
You're a footnote.
之前你还真唬住我了
For a while, you had me fooled.
我还以为我对你动心了
I mean, I thought I heard a heartbeat.
但不是的
But it wasn't a heartbeat.
那只是回声
It was an echo.
我之前爱你...
I loved you...
是因为你把我的想法复述给我
because you recited my own ideas back to me
还假装那是你的
and pretended they were your own.
你想知道真相吗
You want to know the truth?
你还是你妈妈
You're still exactly what you were
让你掉下屋顶那天的那个人
the day your mom let you fall off that roof.
没错
Yeah.
一个可怜的小男孩
Just a sad little boy...
大有潜力  却毫无作为
with a lot of wasted potential.
你去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
11点半多了  你终于来了
It's past 11:30. Nice of you to show up.
过来  看看这个
Come here, you're gonna want to see this.
他们今天都没来上班
None of them showed up for work today.
去哪了呢
Where are they?
尼尔  告诉他
Neil, tell 'em.
他们跳槽去穆特尼了
They all went to work for Mutiny.
意为反叛
没听说过
I've never heard of it.
这才是最有意思的
Well, that's the best part.
欢迎来到穆特尼
好了  你们两个去买X射线管
Okay, I need you guys to buy as many XTs
摆在架子上  一直到放不下
for the shelves as you can until these max out.
好吧  可是调制解调器固件老出毛病
Okay, okay, but the modem firmware is bugging out all over the place.
-我没法预计故障  -好吧
- I can't predict the errors. - Okay--
还得着手写协议  界面  游戏
We need to get onto the protocols, the interface, the games.
-好  -最好找个人专门负责硬件
- Okay. - It'd be awesome to have someone dedicated to hardware.
该死
Shit.
最好是成年人
Preferably an adult.
好吧
Okay.
我不能给你钱
So, I can't pay you,
但可以给你一部分股份
but I can offer you a percentage of the company.
为什么选我
Why me?
我手下全是搞软件的码农
My house is running wild with code monkeys.
我需要个有硬件经验
I need someone with real hardware experience and
注重细节的人
attention to detail.
-你们想做什么  -建立人与人的联系
- Well, what's the idea? - Connecting people.
一拨号  就能用电话线跟真人一起玩游戏
You dial in, you play games across phone lines with real humans.
我们要编写界面  游戏什么的
We're writing the interface, the games, everything.
但电话线不够快啊
But phone lines aren't fast enough.
我有一个相移调幅协议
I've got a phase-shifting and amplitude modulation protocol
能达到9600波特
that breaks 9600 baud.
用户订阅  我们邮寄调制解调器和软件
You subscribe. You get a modem and software in the mail.
等等  你到底什么目的
Wait, what is this really?
是想报复吗
Some sort of revenge hire?
用这种方式来报复戈登
Some screwed-up way of getting back at Gordon?
我可不是
Because I am not some pawn
你们三个变态的博弈中的
in whatever twisted chess match
一个小棋子
the three of you play with each other.
唐娜
Donna.
我很荣幸  谢谢
I'm flattered, thanks.
但还是算了
But, no, thanks.
好吧  随你便
Okay. Suit yourself.
你要见我
You wanted to see me?
-乔  -别说了
- Look, Joe-- - Save your breath.
我没招了
You got me.
程序员都跑了  别想再搞出什么杀手应用了
Coders are gone. Any chance of a killer app is dead.
你说得对  电脑可以了
You're right. It's ready.
好吧
Okay.
其他样机出现此类问题了吗
Did any other test boxes display the same problem?
就那一台
Just the one.
十万台中的一千台  这是1%
A thousand machines out of a hundred thousand, one percent?
退货率很低
Return rate will be less.
不会影响利润率
We won't even feel it in the profit margin.
你什么意思
So, what are you saying, exactly?
发货吧
Ship it.
你在干什么呢
What are you working on?
打印驱动程序
Just a print driver.
裁缝剪裁地怪怪的
I think the tailor cut it weird.
戈登  你穿着太帅气了  真棒
Gordon, that looks so good on you. You look great.
乔肯定会...
Well, you know, Joe's gonna be all--
他是他
Oh, Joe is Joe.
你做自己就好  来
You be yourself. Here.
不好吧
Ah, I don't know.
-等我10分钟  -我们要迟了
- Give me 10 minutes. - We're gonna be late.
这是我的电脑  让他们等吧
Well, it's my computer. They can wait for me.
我已经在跟大力神商讨
I'm already talking to Hercules
计算机外围设备制造商
下一代电脑直接将他们的
about placing their CGA technology
彩色图形配置器技术添加在我们的主板上
directly onto our motherboard for the next iteration.
太棒了
Fantastic.
抱歉  唐娜
I'm sorry-- Donna--
盖尔  抱歉  这是我妻子  唐娜
Gayle, I apologize, this is my wife Donna.
认识你真高兴
Oh, so pleased to meet you.
-谢谢  我也是  -戈登
- Thank you, likewise. - Hey, Gordon,
戈登  过来下
Gordon. Come tell 'em...
你们稍等我一下
Can you guys excuse me for just one moment?
真忙啊
Busy bee.
你是做什么的
So, what do you do?
我现在没有工作
Oh, I-- uh, I'm not working presently.
他剃了胡子好精神啊
So, he looks great without the beard.
-嗯  -看上去更像管事的了
- Yeah. - It makes him look so in charge, you know?
那...
Well...
你卖出了第一台电脑
Well, you sold your first computer.
这倒提醒我了
Mm-hmm-- mm, which reminds me.
我们来这儿干什么
What-- what are we doing in here?
-站在这儿  -好
- Here. Stand right there. - Okay.
戈登
Gordon?
手伸出来
Give me your hand.
我九年前向你许下了一个诺言
I made a promise to you nine years ago.
戈登
Oh, Gordon.
跟原来那个一样
It's just like the original one
多字码密码也是一样的
with the same polyalphabetic cipher.
我好爱你
I "darf" you very "gerp."
我会爱你直到我停止呼吸
I'll "darf" you to the day I "zof."
戈登  他们找你呢
Gordon, they're asking for you.
大家  听我说
All right, everyone, listen up.
请大家前往停车场
I'd like to invite you all out to the parking lot
卡迪夫巨人的第一批电脑
where the first shipment of Cardiff Giants
正在那里等待登上处女航
is waiting to be christened for its maiden voyage.
首先  我想说
first off, I'd like to start by saying that
今晚  我能站在这里
I wouldn't be standing here tonight
站在大家面前
in front of all of you
多亏了乔·麦克米伦
if it weren't for Joe MacMillan.
我们都该感谢他
None of us would be.
有时候你得逼着我们向前进
Sometimes you had to drag us forward kicking and screaming,
但到头来  你是对的
but in the end, you were right.
卡迪夫巨人是你本人的化身
The Cardiff Giant is an incarnation of everything you are.
它体现了你的高瞻远瞩和其影响
It shows the reach and power of your vision
以及你作为领袖的过人能力
and the very best of your abilities as a leader.
敬我的搭档  乔·麦克米伦
To my partner, Joe MacMillan.
乔
To Joe!
还有我妻子  唐娜呢
And to my wife-- where's Donna?
敬我另一位搭档  如果不是她  我会彻底迷失
To my other partner, without whom I'd be completely lost.
我爱你
I love you, honey.
我也爱你  戈登
I love you, too, Gordon.
这辆车将在天明出发
This vessel departs at dawn.
好运  老天保佑
Good luck and Godspeed!
巨人  巨人
Giant! Giant! Giant!
小心头
Watch your head.
等我一下
Hey, just give me a minute.
难以置信
I can't believe it.
感觉好不真实
It just doesn't seem real.
是啊
Yeah.
明早办公室见
Well, I'll see you in the office in the morning,
-一大早  -到时见
- bright and early. - See you then.
谢谢了
Thanks.
谢谢你做的一切
For everything.
记得乔跟踪我们去看《绝地大反击》吗
'Member when Joe followed us to "Return of the Jedi"?
你说他真看那部电影了吗
Do you think he even watched the movie?
没有
I know he didn't.
几个月前  我说那些程序员是一群依娃祖人
A few months ago, I called the coders a bunch of Ewoks.
他根本不知道什么意思
He had no idea what I was talking about.
那他怎么会有爆米花
Then why did he have popcorn?
他大概只是想装装样子吧
I think he just wanted to look more normal.
该死的
Son of a bitch.
有人撞了我们吗
Did somebody hit us?
这可是保时捷
You just hit a Porsche, buddy.
希望你车保赔得起
Hope you got great insurance.
待在车里
Stay in the car.
你干什么啊  你撞坏了我的...
Man! What the hell, You busted the-- ah!
-钥匙  -在车里
- Keys! - They're in the car.
等等  我妻子
Wait! Wait, my wife!
我妻子
My wife!
该死
Oh, shit.
更多了
Even more had.
好吧  琼妮要酥脆的  海莉要奶油的
All right, so Joanie's crunchy and Haley's creamy.
不  我要奶油的  酥脆的好恶心
No, I'm creamy. Crunchy's gross.
我讨厌奶油的
I really hate creamy.
那杏味的呢
How about apricot?
恶心死了
That's really disgusting.
你们午餐盒为什么都黏黏的
Why do you have gummies all over your lunch box?
-我们要吃的  -那是餐后甜点
- We were gonna eat that. - That's my dessert for after lunch.
-糖太多了  -不多
- That's too much sugar. - No, it's not.
布拉斯韦尔一家周末搬走了
The Braswells moved over the weekend.
你看到搬家车了吗
Did you see? There was a truck.
姑娘们  出去上车上去吧
Hey, girls, why don't you go out to the van?
我还会像往常一样  5点回家
All right, I'll be home by 5:00 as usual
萝丝会来接孩子
and Rose will pick up the kids.
爱你哦
Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
-你们系好安全带了吧  -嗯
- You guys all buckled up? - Yep.
拿好午餐
Here are your lunches.
-我肯定不会吃的  -那是当然
- I already know I'm not gonna eat it. - That's for sure.
唐娜  那晚有那么一刻
Donna, there was a moment that night
我以为
when I thought--
我以为我要失去你了
I thought I was gonna lose you
我绝不想失去你
and I never want to lose you.
我不能失去你  但除此之外
I can't lose you, but more than that,
你不能一直闷坐在这儿
you can't just sit here and stew.
你该去做你想做的事
You should do whatever it is that you want to do.
来卡迪夫工作吧
Come work at Cardiff.
我想要你做首席工程师
I want you to be the head engineer.
我什么都要管  根本忙不过来
I'm stretched thin running everything,
不管我们接下来做什么  一定要大
and whatever we do next, it needs to be big.
唐娜  这需要你
Donna, it-- it needs you.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢你  这对我意义重大  -嗯
- Thank you, you don't know what it means to me... - Yeah?
-你能来问我  -当然
- ...for you to ask. - Of course.
但我觉得我现在去卡迪夫不合适
But I don't think that Cardiff is the best place for me right now.
好吧
Uh, o-okay. Okay, well,
你该去
you know, you should work
你想去的地方工作
wherever it is that you want to work, okay?
去你想去的地方
Go wherever your heart takes you.
不论如何  我都会支持你
I'm gonna support you no matter what.
我最近一直在想
I've been thinking.
前一阵有人提出要雇佣我
I actually got an offer from somewhere else a little while ago
我打算接受这份邀请
and I'm gonna take it.
什么
What?
这太棒了
That-- that-- that's fantastic.
太好了
That-- that's great news.
是哪啊
Where?
大家听好
All right, everyone listen up.
我想让大家记住几件事
Uh, I just want you guys to keep a few things in mind.
第一  我不是你们的老板
One, I'm not your boss.
这里没有职称
Nobody here has titles.
只有名字
Your title is your first name.
我叫卡梅伦
Mine is Cameron.
-你好  卡梅伦  -你们好
- Hi, Cameron. - Hello.
而且这不是我一个人的创业  是我们的
Also, this isn't my thing. This is our thing.
所以我们是种瓜得瓜种豆得豆
Which means you'll get out of it exactly what you put into it.
我要付出一切
For me, it's everything.
对我们大家都该是如此
For all of us, it should be everything.
否则何必要做呢
Otherwise why even do it at all?
嗯
Right.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有最后一样
Uh, and just one last thing.
很多人会希望我们失败
A lot of people are gonna want us to fail.
因为我们是未来
But that's because we're the future
没什么比那更可怕的了
and there's nothing scarier than that.
说得好
Yes!
好了  向未来进发
All right! To the future!
-好  -未来
- Yes! - The future!
唐娜·克拉克
Donna Clark!
欢迎来到穆特尼
Hello, welcome to Mutiny.
与其他便携电脑不同
"Unlike other portables,
巨人令人眼前一亮
the Giant is not a strain on the back,"
一堆废话
blah-blah-blah.
总体来说  运行速度很快
"Overall, it's pretty fast."
不错  而且物美价廉
There you go. "Also a wise value at such a low price..."
-听上去不错  -嗯
- Sounds good to me. - Yeah.
虽然强光下液晶屏看起来比较费劲
Uh, "Despite the LCD screen being hard to read in bright light."
瞎说
Bullshit.
他拿去海滩了吗
What did he do, take it to the beach?
好了  这句
Okay, here we go.
总体上  卡迪夫巨人便携个人电脑
"Overall, the Cardiff Giant Portable PC
是一个朴实而强有力的竞争者
stands out as a strong contender in no-frills computing accommodation."
-好啊  -这话是绝对没错
- Okay. - We can take that to the bank.
不错吧
That's good, right?
十万台...
A hundred thousand units...
接下来呢
So, what's next?
我们接下来做什么
What are we gonna do next?
如果乔·麦克米伦在
If Joe MacMillan were here,
他大概会让我们造飞船吧
he'd have us building a damn spaceship.
找到他了吗
Anybody ever find that guy?
他好像在凯尔餐馆做厨师
I think he's a fry cook at Kel's.
下午好  要加油吗
Afternoon. Need a fill-up?
不用  谢谢
Uh, no, thanks.
你要去哪
Where you headed?
菲斯克天文台
Fiske Observatory.
是在这一带吗  地图上没有
Is that around here? I can't find it on the map.
因为那是两年前才建起来的
That's 'cause they just built it two years ago.
是那边吧
It's that way, though, right?
嗯  几十英里吧
Sure, a couple dozen miles.
离这儿一小时远处有条交流道
You know there's an access road about an hour away
由南往北
coming in from the south.
这边都是土路和老拖车
This way is just dirt roads and old horse trails.
都是丘陵地
Raw hills country.
我想走风景比较好的路
Thought I'd take the scenic route.
我可以把卡车留在这儿吗
Is it all right if I leave my truck here?
是观星的吗
Hmm, some kind of stargazer, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
我替你看着车
I'll watch your truck for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
菲斯克就一个人
You know there ain't nobody up at Fiske, save the one.
一年里大部分时候都住那儿
Lives there most of the year.
-她下来过吗  -不怎么下来
- She ever come down? - Not really.
在镇上见过她一两次  买杂货
See her in town once in a while buying groceries.
人还行  不知道是不是愿见客
Pleasant enough. Not sure she's used to visitors.
你可别挨枪子了
Don't get yourself shot.
我会小心的
I'll be careful.
你想去看什么啊
What do you want to see up there?
莱夫
Lev.
这是做硬件的  唐娜
This is hardware, Donna.
嗯  你想看看...
Yeah, do you want to see your...
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
潇湘月影
小酸奶!
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
小花豆
翻译
木浅薰
somehacker
翻译
草草
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第十集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
大伟昔